



Ishrak Latif

Date of birth: 08/08/1996 | **Nationality:** Bangladeshi | **Phone number:**

(+880) 1712500637 (Home) | **Email address:** <u>ishrak10319@gmail.com</u> | **Website:**

https://github.com/ishraklatif | Website:

www.linkedin.com/in/ishrak-latif-a79235212 | Website: ishraklatif.github.io |

Address: 96/1, North Jatrabari, 1232, Dhaka, Bangladesh (Home)

ABOUT ME

Software Engineer and retired army Lieutenant with 5+ years experience. Experienced with software development life cycle from planning to all the way to production and delivery. Inclined towards calculus for optimisation and RNN going towards LLM. Currently working on document embedding for applying RAG framework as a research project.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/02/2016 - 25/12/2021 Dhaka, Bangladesh

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING Bangladesh University of Professionals

Address Mirpur Cantonment, Mirpur, 1216, Dhaka, Bangladesh | Website https://bup.edu.bd |

Field of study Computer Science and Engineering | Final grade 2.87/4 |

Thesis Automated Eyeball Controlled Wheelchair for Physically Challenged People

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2016 - 25/06/2021 Dhaka, Bangladesh

LIEUTENANT BANGLADESH ARMY

- Maintaining communication from command post to gun post
- · Maintaining communication from command post to Regimental HQ
- Maintaining communication of Divisional HQ orders to Commanding Officer of the regiment
- Execute orders from Commanding Officer based on divisional and regimental HQ directions.
- Assisting Brigade Major maintain communication from Divisional HQ to Brigade Regiments during appointment as G3 ops 9th Brigade.

01/01/2023 - CURRENT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AZTECH VALLEY

- Planning and design of software processes and product owner
- Creating and presenting demo for client
- Selection of framework and tools required for development
- Managing team progress and building communication with client for updates
- Deployment on virtual server and product delivery

01/05/2023 - CURRENT Dhaka, Bangladesh

CONSULTANT ENGINEER BD THAI GROUP

- Planning of purchase and integration of new technologies with Managing Director.
- Conduct meeting with stakeholders on behalf of the company for software and hardware purchase.
- Manage teams from supplier during calibration and setting up purchased hardware.
- Assist managing director in meetings with government officials during product presentation.

CONSULTANT ENGINEER DHAKA NATIONAL MEDICAL INSTITUTE HOSPITAL

- Planning of purchase and integration of new technologies with Project Director.
- Conduct meeting with stakeholders on behalf of the company for software and hardware purchase.
- Manage teams from supplier during calibration and setting up purchased hardware.
- Assist and conduct presentation for the director in meetings with health ministry for fund allocation of new technology

01/01/2021 - 02/2021 Dhaka, Bangladesh

INTERNSHIP CSL SOFTWARE RESOURCES

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B2	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Graphic interfaces development for SCADA with WinCC | programming: Python, MATLAB and SQL | C, C+ +c C#